How to play the game:

Launch the game from the executable folder by double clicking on the minesweeper.html. Once the game is loaded you can complete the form. You can set how many columns, rows and mines do you want to have. Start a new game by hitting the 'Start new game button.' Play the game by clicking on the fields one by one. Your goals is to reveal each field excluding the ones that contain a mine. To learn, where the mines are, check the field you have been clicked. If the field does not contain a number, there are no mines in the immediate vicinity. If you see a number in a field, that means that in the immediate vicinity there are that number of mines. It is possible to tag a field with the right mouse button. Do this, if you suspect that there is a mine underneath. This way you can ensure that you don't click that field by accident. To un-tag a field, right click on it again. 

Legend of signs

During gameplay:
- dark brown field: unrevealed field, it may contain a mine
- light brown field without any text: blank field, there are no mines around it
- light field with a number: it indicates, how many mines are in the neighboring fields
- a maroon field with a ⚠ (warning) sign: indicates a flagged field

After the game ends:
- a black field with a ☢ (radioactive) sign: a mine
- an orange field with a ⚐ (empty flag) sign: a field flagged, but not containing any mines
- a green field with a ⚑ (filled flag) sign: a field flagged and containing a mine
- a green field with a ☢ (radioactive) sign: a mine not touched nor flagged

The game was tested on Windows only, on the following browsers:

Google Chrome Version 61.0.3163.100
Mozilla Firefox Version 56.0
Microsoft Edge Version 40.15063.0.0
Internet Explorer Version 11.608.15063.0